NICK VEIL

859.533.4983 n.veil@live.com Lexington, KY

Overview

Seven years of customer service experience specializing in field installation, training, and event support. Five years of progressive project management experience in product testing and capital additions. Two years of department management experience building a high performance team, improving workflow efficiency, and developing departmental goals in alignment with budget and vision. Bachelor's Degree in Administration and Associates Degree in Electronics.

SKILLS

Key Skills: DMAIC Process Improvement • Problem Solving • Mechanical and Electronic

Troubleshooting • Root Cause Analysis • Conflict Management • Failure Mode Effects

Analysis (FMEA) • SMART Goal Setting • Positive Management Leadership •

Commitment Based Leadership • Negotiation

Management Tools: ORACLE Performance Management System • KRONOS Time & Attendance •

ORACLE E-Business Suite (Purchase Order, Time/Expense, Workflow) • Visual Studio •

Team Foundation Server (TFS) • Microsoft Project

Technical Tools: Windows XP/7/8.1 • Microsoft Office 2013 • Microsoft Visio • VBA for Excel • Minitab

16 • AutoCAD

Training / Workshop: Positive Management Leadership Workshop (2014) • Commitment Based Leadership

Program (2013) • Lean Six Sigma Black Belt – Minitab (2013) • FMEA – Quality One

(2013) • LabVIEW Core 1 & Core 2 (2013)

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

R/D Manager (Reliability and Testing) | Itron, Inc. | Owenton, KY

2013 - 2017

Manage a dedicated reliability department which provides test and analysis services to the customer, global R/D department, product sustaining teams.

Highlights:

- Improved on-time delivery of over 500 tests from 93% to 98.5% through process and workflow improvement initiatives.
- Increased reliability portfolio 62% by adding 5 new programs in two years as manager.
- Created Excel tools for department team members to accurately track and process over 4500 samples.

Projects:

European Natural Gas Test Rack – Project manager • RODI Water Treatment System – Project Manager • Salt Fog Test Quality Improvements – Project Manager • Work Order Management – Project Coordinator

R/D Technician II | Itron, Inc. | Owenton, KY

2010 - 2013

Design and organize specialized test configurations to pursue new business opportunities, conduct root cause analysis of special warranty claims, and validate new designs and innovations.

Highlights:

- Conducted approval testing of third party electronic index as final piece for an awarded 1.5 million meter contract.
- Authored paper on behalf of Itron submitted to the American National Standard Institute (ANSI), reviewing alternative test apparatus for the Accelerated Weathering Test within the B109.1 standard.
- Enhanced existing diagnostic tools through automated data collection hardware and software additions.

Projects:

Vacuum Test System – Project Manager • Natural Gas Test Rack – Project Coordinator

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE - CONTINUED

Field Service Technician | Daktronics, Ink | Norman, OK

2006 - 2010

Provided installation, training and repair services for digital displays and scoreboards to businesses, churches, schools, universities and professional sports franchises.

Highlights:

- Developed outstanding rapport with many prominent Collegiate and Professional sports organizations.
- Directed intern workers for game day support of University of Oklahoma football.
- Provided game day preparation and support for first 16 games of the Oklahoma City Thunder (NBA) inaugural season.

Projects:

University of Oklahoma – Project Installation • Oklahoma State University – Project Installation • Tulsa University – Project Installation • Oklahoma City Thunder – Project Installation

Electronic Technician II | John Deere Electronic Solutions | Fargo, ND

2003 - 2006

Supported new product introduction through specialized testing and failure analysis reporting to project and manufacturing engineers.

Highlights:

• Selected as sole technician to evaluate and report on new product defects and accelerated testing issues.

Customer Service Technician | Office Systems Inc. | Fargo, ND

2000 - 2003

Installed, repaired and provided operator training of copy systems, fax machines, and printers.

Highlights:

• Selected as top 20 finalist nationwide for Lanier Service Award

EDUCATION

Web Development Awesome Inc U	2017 – Current
BA Administration University of Oklahoma	2008 - 2012
AAS Electronics Technology Bismarck State College	1997 – 1999

VOLUNTEER WORK

Pinnacle Pirates Swim Team Parent Volunteer	2013 – Current
Faith Lutheran Learning Center Committee Member	2011 - Current
Faith Lutheran Church Church Council	2011 - 2015
Faith Lutheran Church Sunday School Teacher	2012 - 2013
South Eastern Cal Ripken Fall League Parent Coach	2011 - 2012